Kadir Berk Tavlı

 ♀ Istanbul, Ümraniye|Turkey
 ➡ kberktavli@gmail.com
 ┗ +90 531 967 1541

PROFILE

Hello, I am Kadir Berk Tavli. I live in Ümraniye, Istanbul as a recently graduated (end of May) Computer Engineer from Karabük University and I am passionate about Android application development. With my two compulsory internships and long-term internship experience, I have improved my application development skills in Kotlin language and gained knowledge about Android operating system, common 3rd party libraries and application architecture. I adopt Clean Code principles and have a good command of source code versioning management. I have strong problem solving and reporting skills, am prone to teamwork and closely follow the developments in mobile technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Android Developer Longterm Intern

Abonesepeti ∂

02/2024 - 05/2024 Istanbul, Turkey

I have focussed on network programming libraries such as Retrofit. I have focused on basic and advanced topics such as accessing web services, exchanging data and communicating with the server (HTTP requests).I have developed and implemented applications covering topics such as interacting with RESTful API's, data transformations, error handling and security.

- CryptoRetrofit ∅
- RetrofitGuide ⊘

Android Developer Intern

Abonesepeti ∂

07/2023 - 09/2023 Istanbul, Turkey

During this internship, I had the opportunity to learn the syntax of the Kotlin programming language, user interface design, database integration and basic application logic. I also improved my communication and co-operation skills within the team.

- YoutubeClone ∂
- CalculatorApp ∂
- <u>NavigationComponentUsage</u> ∅
- <u>PizzaOrderScreen</u> ⊘

EDUCATION

Computer Engineering / 4nd year student / GPA 2.98
Karabuk University

2019 - 2024 Karabuk, Turkey

SKILLS

Kotlin, Java, OOP, SQL

Firebase, RestFul, MySQL, Android Studio, Git, Github

LANGUAGES

English C2 / Studied a prep year in Karabuk University

COURSES

Android Mobile Application Course: Kotlin & Java / Atil Samancioglu Udemv

Android Bootcamp Kotlin Course / Kasım Adalan Udemy